Inventory of the Chapel Programs Collection, 1871 - 1972
Chapel Programs Collection, 1871 - 1972
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
1000-142
1.25
3
Wesleyan University's Memorial Chapel was built and dedicated in 1871. It was intended to commemorate those Wesleyan students and alumni who fought in the Civil War, and later additions of stained glass windows acknowledge student service in other wars. The Memorial Chapel has been the main site of religious ceremonies at Wesleyan since 1871. The services were primarily Methodist.
The Chapel Programs Collection consists of programs from regular religious services, as well as vesper services, university services, and special dedicatory and memorial services.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Collected by Olin Library.
Historical Note
Wesleyan University's Memorial Chapel was built and dedicated in 1871. It was intended to commemorate those Wesleyan students and alumni who fought in the Civil War, and later additions of stained glass windows acknowledge student service in other wars. The Memorial Chapel has been the main site of religious ceremonies at Wesleyan since 1871. The services were primarily Methodist.
Collection Overview
The Chapel Programs Collection consists of programs from regular religious services, as well as vesper services, university services, and special dedicatory and memorial services. There are also eight bound volumes of chapel programs from various services and events dating from 1929 to 1945.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--History.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Religion.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Buildings.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Chapel Programs, 1882-1969
  Chapel Programs are from regular Sunday morning services at the church.
  See also the Bound Volumes series for materials from 1929-1945.
  - 1882-1887 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1933-1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1958-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Chapel Special Services Programs, 1871-1972
  Chapel Special Services Programs include memorial services, dedications, commemorations (particularly in regard to war events), and commencement-related services.
  - 1871-1921 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1924-1932 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1933-1938 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1942-1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1945-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- University Services, 1920-1934
  University Services were religious services held in conjunction with commencement ceremonies.
  - 1920-1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1930-1934 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Vesper Services, 1909-1932
  Vesper services were weekly religious services held in the evening.
  - 1909 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1910 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - 1911 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1912 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1913 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1914 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1915 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1916 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1926-1932 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Bound Volumes, 1929-1945
  These volumes have programs from various services and events pasted in chronologically.
  - 1929-1931 (Volume 1)
  - 1931-1933 (Volume 2)
  - 1933-1935 (Volume 3)
  - 1935-1937 (Volume 4)
  - 1937-1939 (Volume 5)
  - 1939-1941 (Volume 6)
  - 1941-1943 (Volume 7)
  - 1943-1945 (Volume 8)